To output feedback upon our validation result, I have to go to my input component and therefore each
Dorulama sonucumuza geri bildirim gnderiyorsunuz Giri bileenine gitmeliyim ve bu nedenle her girdi esi
input element, I in the end want to add a special class to that element
bu eye zel bir snf eklemek iin sonuna girilmelidir.
if it is invalid.
Eer geersizse.
So my classes here have to become more dynamic. In the end,
Bu yzden snfmn bu yl sonunda daha dinamik hale gelmesi lazm.
I will add a new constant which I'll name inputClasses which is an array which at the beginning is just
Balangta sadece snflarn input eleman olan bir dizi olan giri snflarn isimlendiren yeni
classes.inputElement,
bir sabit ekleyeceim.
I always want to attach this. Now on the individual elements here, I'll replace classes.inputElement with
Her zaman bunu imdi bireysel elere eklemek veya Klaas'n giri esini dizimle deitirmek
my array
istiyorum.
So with my input, whoops, inputClasses, this array I just created here and I'll join it with a whitespace,
Bub'un girdi snflaryla bu diziyi imdi burada oluturduum giri ile birlikte tm dizge snflarm snflarn
so to concatenate all my string classes into one long string where the classes are separated. Now inputClasses
ayrld tek bir uzun dize birletirmek iin bir bolukla katacam
also needs to receive the invalid property
Giri snflar ayrca Velayat zelliinde D'yi almas gerekiyor.
if the input is invalid and I'll do this with a if check, that check is independent of the type of the input
Giri kadifede ise bunu bir ek derinlii kontrol ile yapacam giri trne bal deildir.
so I only need to do it once at the beginning.
Bu yzden sadece bir kereliine banda yapmam lazm.
I'll check if props.invalid is set to true, if it is then I'll push a new class to my inputClasses,
Porsiyonun geersiz olup olmadn kontrol edeceim, o zaman, giri snflarna yeni bir snf basacam.
the
D.
invalid.css class
Geersiz C s S snf.
and of course not like that,
Ve elbette yle deil.
Classes.Invalid,
Snf geersiz.
I need to define that class.
Bu snf tanmlamam gerekiyor.
So now, this is pushed to my inputClasses which are then attached in a string way to my elements, for
Bu yzden imdi bu, girdi snflarmma itiliyor ve bu girdi snflarm, daha sonra, doru veya yanl olan
that I need to receive an invalid prop which is true or false
geersiz pervaneyi almak iin benim elerime dizgiyle balanyor.
and I also need to find some styling. So I'll simply go to my input element or to the css file for
Ve ayrca baz stil bulmam gerekiyor, bu nedenle giri esine veya giri bileeni iin C S
the input component and add an invalid class,
S dosyasna gidip geersiz bir snf ekleyeceim.
that's the class I'm referring to here,
Bahsettiim snf budur.
the class I try to push to my array.
Snfm dizilimime itmeye alyorum.
Now there you can set up any style you want,
imdi istediiniz herhangi bir stili ayarlayabilirsiniz.
I'll simply set up a border which is 1px solid and red maybe and a background-color of light red,
Hepsi basite bir piksel kat ve krmz belki bir ereve ve ak krmz bir arka plan rengi belki
maybe salmon, let's have a look, you can even choose a little bit of a lighter red, something like that.
Sahlman' ayarlayarak bir gz atn ve hatta biraz daha ak krmz bir ey sein.
Now to see that effect, I have to go back to the contact data and there, I now need to pass that invalid
imdi bu etkiyi grmek iin balant verisine geri dnmeliyim ve imdi geersiz
property to the input I render,
mlk renderladm girdiye geirmem gerekiyor.
so here I'll add invalid and invalid is some data
Yani burada geersiz ve geersiz baz veriler.
I again now have on my form element, on the form element in the config object which just as a reminder
benim form emde yine varm; bu, hatrlatc olarak sadaki l nesneleri belirtiyor.
refers to that object here on the right
atma nesnesinin form esinde
in our state orderForm property. There we have this valid property, valid of course tracks whether the
Eyalet Sipari Formu mlkmzde elbette ki geerli geerli mlkmz var ve formun geerli
form is valid or not,
olup olmadn izliyor.
I want to pass an invalid property, so I will access valid and then reverse it by adding an exclamation
Geerli bir zellii gemek istiyorum, bylece x geerli olacak ve bata bir yanl iareti ekleyerek tersine evirip, gerei
mark at the beginning to turn true to false and false to true because I'm passing the opposite. With
yanla ve drdnc doruya dndrdmden tersiyle geiyorum nk bunu kaydetme ve gidelim. haritaya geri dnn
that, let's save this and let's go back to the app and now, everything is invalid at the beginning which
ve en bata ve / veya bir ey mantkl olsa da
makes sense. As soon as I enter something though, things become valid, the zip code only after five characters
balangta her eyin geersiz olduunu bilin, ancak SIP kodu yalnzca be karakterden sonra Valot olur
and not with more.
ve daha fazla deil.
So we can see that now indeed we are correctly returning information about the validity,
Dolaysyla unu grebiliriz ki imdi geerlilikle ilgili bilgileri doru bir ekilde geri getiriyoruz.
we also see though that it's not that friendly to start with a page which, with a form that's just
Ayn zamanda, bir dorulama kural gzetlememize ramen, bir sayfayla balamak o kadar kolay deil ya
red, we also see that our dropdown is always red even though we have no validation rules there,
da hepimiz l grdmz ya da drdmz okumaya devam eden bir formla daima okunuyor.
so we definitely need some fine tuning.
Bu yzden kesinlikle biraz ince ayar yapmaya ihtiyacmz var.
Let's start with the dropdown,
Ancak alr menden balayn.
we shouldn't always add invalid, props.invalid
Geersiz sahne zarflar daima eklememeliyiz.
true or false,
Doru ya da yanl.
that's nice to have but we have an issue in cases like our dropdown where we have no rules.
Olmas gzel ama kurallarmzn olmad alr men gibi durumlarda sorun yayoruz.
So what I should also check if it's invalid
yleyse geersiz olup olmadn ne kontrol etmeliyim.
and if we maybe have like props.shouldValidate property. I now can set up shouldValidate in my contact
Ve eer belki sahiplik dorulama mlkiyet imkn verdiysek, ayarlayabildiim mlkiyet gibi imdi de girdiimize ek
data as an additional property I passed to my input and shouldValidate should only be true if my object
bir mlk olarak geirilen iletiim verilerinde geerlilik kazanmal ve sipari formundaki nesnemiz bir
in the orderForm has a validation object,
dorulama nesnesine sahipse geerliliini salamal.
my delivery method which is the dropdown in the end hasn't
Teslimat metodum decek ve sonunda da olmayacakt.
so it shouldn't validate at all.
Dolaysyla hi dorulamamaldr.
So here I will simply pass form element config validation
Yani burada sadece dorulama sahte olamaz form eleman geirecek.
and if the validation property isn't set as for my dropdown, this will return true or false and therefore
yanl dndrr ve dolaysyla burada giri bileenimdeki kontrol almazsa ve o derste asla bulunmazsa, bunu yapar.
this if check in my input component here will not run and it will never get the invalid class,
Ve dorulama zellii benim alr mende olduu gibi ayarlanmadysa Bu, doru veya
so now we can see the dropdown is not treated as invalid anymore.
Dolaysyla alr mennn artk geersiz saylmadn grebiliyoruz.
We also have to ensure that everything is invalid right from the start,
Hepimizin batan beri her eyin geersiz olduundan emin olmalyz.
so we should also track whether an input has been touched by the user or not,
Dolaysyla, bir girdinin kullanc tarafndan dokunulmadn da izlemeliyiz.
let's do this in the next lecture.
Bunu bir sonraki dersimizde yapalm.